Guide to the National Federation of Grain Cooperatives records, 1946-1976.
National Federation of Grain Cooperatives records,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
National Federation of Grain Cooperatives records, 1946-1976.
2940
National Federation of Grain Cooperatives.
53 cubic ft.
Legal documents, reports, correspondence,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Legislation; congressional committee hearings, comments, and press releases regarding agriculture law and legislation; press releases of farmers' associations; correspondence concerning laws, taxation, etc.; material on cooperatives and associations; records of commodity prices; newsletters, reports, memos, etc. concerning import quotas; material on the Uniform Grain Storage Agreement; and other records of agricultural associations and laws and regulations affecting agriculture. Persons named in the records include Martin Abraham Abrahamsen, Dean Acheson, George David Aiken, Carl Bert Albert, John A. Baker, Louis Hyman Bean, Ezra Taft Benson, Walter C. Berger, John Bird, Mortimer Maxwell Caplin, John Alexander Carroll, J.M. Chambers, Willard W. Cochrane, Lloyd H. Davis, Douglas Dillon, Robert J. Dole, Paul Douglas, Milton Stover Eisenhower, Paul L. Farris, William Farris, Orville L. Freeman, Guy Mark Gillette, H.D. Godfrey, Roy F. Hendrickson, Hubert Humphrey, Dr. A. Ladru Jensen, C. Warner Johnson, Edwin Clark Johnson, Lyndon B. Johnson, Robert Samuel Kerr, William Leonard Langer, Catharine May, Fred Maywald, Eugene J. McCarthy, Wilbur D. Mills, Karl E. Mundt, Charles S. Murphy, Lawrence F. O'Brien, Albert H. Quie, Don L. Short, Edward John Thye, Thomas F. Toohey, Horace Jeremiah Voorhis, Henry Agard Wallace, John Clarence Watts, and Jamie L. Whitten.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Legislation; congressional committee hearings, comments, and press releases regarding agriculture law and legislation; press releases of farmers' associations; correspondence concerning laws, taxation, etc.; material on cooperatives and associations; records of commodity prices; newsletters, reports, memos, etc. concerning import quotas; material on the Uniform Grain Storage Agreement; and other records of agricultural associations and laws and regulations affecting agriculture. Persons named in the records include Martin Abraham Abrahamsen, Dean Acheson, George David Aiken, Carl Bert Albert, John A. Baker, Louis Hyman Bean, Ezra Taft Benson, Walter C. Berger, John Bird, Mortimer Maxwell Caplin, John Alexander Carroll, J.M. Chambers, Willard W. Cochrane, Lloyd H. Davis, Douglas Dillon, Robert J. Dole, Paul Douglas, Milton Stover Eisenhower, Paul L. Farris, William Farris, Orville L. Freeman, Guy Mark Gillette, H.D. Godfrey, Roy F. Hendrickson, Hubert Humphrey, Dr. A. Ladru Jensen, C. Warner Johnson, Edwin Clark Johnson, Lyndon B. Johnson, Robert Samuel Kerr, William Leonard Langer, Catharine May, Fred Maywald, Eugene J. McCarthy, Wilbur D. Mills, Karl E. Mundt, Charles S. Murphy, Lawrence F. O'Brien, Albert H. Quie, Don L. Short, Edward John Thye, Thomas F. Toohey, Horace Jeremiah Voorhis, Henry Agard Wallace, John Clarence Watts, and Jamie L. Whitten.
SUBJECTS
Names:
National Federation of Grain Cooperatives.; Abrahamsen, Martin A. (Martin Abraham), 1908-; Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971.; Aiken, George D. (George David), 1892-1984.; Albert, Carl Bert, 1908-2000.; Baker, John A.; Bean, Louis H. (Louis Hyman), 1896-1994.; Benson, Ezra Taft.; Berger, Walter C.; Bird, John.; Caplin, Mortimer Maxwell, 1916-; Carroll, John Alexander.; Chambers, John M.; Cochrane, Willard W. (Willard Wesley), 1914-2012.; Davis, Lloyd H., 1919-; Dillon, Douglas.; Dole, Robert J., 1923-; Douglas, Paul.; Eisenhower, Milton Stover, 1899-1985.; Farris, Paul L.; Farris, William S.; Freeman, Orville L.; Gillette, Guy Mark, 1879-1973.; Godfrey, H. D.; Hendrickson, Roy F.; Humphrey, Hubert (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978.; Jensen, A. Ladru, Dr.; Johnson, C. Warner (Clayton Warner), 1930-; Johnson, Edwin Clark.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Kerr, Robert Samuel, 1896-1963.; Langer, William L. (William Leonard), 1896-1977.; May, Catharine.; Maywald, Fred.; McCarthy, Eugene J., 1916-2005.; Mills, Wilbur D. (Wilbur Daigh), 1909-1992.; Mundt, Karl E. (Karl Earl), 1900-1974.; Murphy, Charles S. (Charles Springs), 1909-; O'Brien, Lawrence F.; Quie, Albert H., 1923-; Short, Don L. (Don Levingston), 1903-1982.; Thye, Edward John, 1896-1969.; Toohey, Thomas F.; Voorhis, Jerry, 1901-1984.; Wallace, Henry A. (Henry Agard), 1888-1965.; Watts, John Clarence, 1902-1971.; Whitten, Jamie L.; Abrahamsen, Martin A. (Martin Abraham), 1908-; Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971; Aiken, George D. (George David), 1892-1984; Albert, Carl Bert, 1908-2000; Baker, John A.; Bean, Louis H. (Louis Hyman), 1896-1994; Benson, Ezra Taft; Bird, John; Caplin, Mortimer Maxwell, 1916-; Carroll, John Alexander; Chambers, John M.; Cochrane, Willard W. (Willard Wesley), 1914-2012.; Davis, Lloyd H., 1919-; Dillon, Douglas; Dole, Robert J., 1923-; Douglas, Paul; Eisenhower, Milton Stover, 1899-1985; Farris, William S.; Freeman, Orville L.; Johnson, C. Warner (Clayton Warner), 1930-; Johnson, Edwin Clark; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973; Kerr, Robert S. (Robert Samuel), 1896-1963; Langer, William L. (William Leonard), 1896-1977; McCarthy, Eugene J., 1916-2005; Mills, Wilbur D. (Wilbur Daigh), 1909-1992; Mundt, Karl E. (Karl Earl), 1900-1974; Murphy, Charles S. (Charles Springs), 1909-; O'Brien, Lawrence F.; Quie, Albert H., 1923-; Thye, Edward John, 1896-1969; Voorhis, Jerry, 1901-1984; Wallace, Henry A. (Henry Agard), 1888-1965; Whitten, Jamie L.; Berger, Walter C.; Farris, Paul L.; Gillette, Guy Mark, 1879-1973; Godfrey, H. D.; Hendrickson, Roy F.; Humphrey, Hubert (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978; Jensen, A. Ladru, Dr; May, Catharine; Maywald, Fred; Short, Don L. (Don Levingston), 1903-1982; Toohey, Thomas F.; Watts, John Clarence, 1902-1971
Subjects:
Agriculture.; Agriculture, Cooperative.; Agricultural laws and legislation.; Agricultural laws and legislation; Agriculture; Agriculture, Cooperative
Form and Genre Terms:
Bills (legislative records).; Newsletters.; Press releases.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Series I. Agricultural Act
Series II. Series II. Co-op Taxes
Series III. Series III. Import Quotas
Series IV. Series IV. Uniform Grain Storage Agreement (UGSA)
Series V. Series V. Assorted Materials
Series VI. Series VI. Chronological Files
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Agricultural Act
  - Agricultural Act: "Prosperity and Progress for the Farmer and Rural America", 1968-02-27 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Pres LBJ, statement, 18pp, plus summary statement
  - Agricultural Act, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Legislative bills
  - Food For Peace, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Congress Record, Senate and House debates and comments
  - Agricultural Act of 1965, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Clippings; press releases; bills; memos; statements; House Committee on Agriculture; wheat; Secretary of Agriculture; Senate Committee on Agricultre and Forestry; Bob Dole, M.C., Kansas
  - Agricultural Act of 1965 (with annotations), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Agricultural Act, 1964-04-11 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Copies, Public Law 88-297,regarding cotton and wheat (multiple copies)
  - Agricultural Press Releases, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    House Committee on Agriculture
  - Agricultural Act, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Public Law 88-26, Feed Grain Act (copies); hearings; Feed Grain Act 1963; miscellaneous statements and reports regarding agriculture and wheat
  - Agricultural Act of 1962, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Correspondence; memo.; regarding the act; Hubert Humphrey; Milton R. Young; National Council of Farmer Cooperatives; Kerr Grain Corporation, Oregon
  - Agricultural Act, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Bills and messages regarding Act of 1962
  - Agricultural Act, 1962-02 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Bills; statements; correspondence regarding 1962 Act: Roy F. Hendrickson statement; Orville L. Freeman before Senate Committee on Agriculture and Forestry; National Association of Wheat Growers, Glen L. Bayne, President; National Council of Farmer Cooperatives; Press Release, National Farmers Union
  - Agricultural Act, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Bills regarding Act of 1962
  - Agricultural Act (Public Law 87-128), 1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Bills, mostly, regarding Act of 1961
  - Agricultural Act -- USDA, President J. Kennedy, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Testimony, statements, memo., press releases, regarding Act of 1961; O.L. Freeman; "Last working draft" Administration Confidential Agricultural Bill; Testimony, O.L. Freeman, Senate Agricultural Committee; E.M. Norton, national Milk Producers Federation before Senate Committee on Agriculture and Forestry
  - Agricultural Act, 1961-05-1961-07 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Statements regarding: Cooperative League of the USA, Jerry Voorhis to Senator Paul Douglas, letter, Canton, South Dakota, regarding legislation; Albert Lowenfels, NY State; National Association of Wheat Growers, before House Committee on Agriculture
  - NFGC, Directors, 1961 Farm Bill, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Correspondence regarding Farm Bill, either positive, negative, neutral
  - Agricultural Act, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    "Wheat Marketing Act of 1960" description, 5 pp. memo
  - Agricultural Act, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Press releases, statements regarding National Farmers Union, House Subcommittee on Wheat; Pres. Eisenhower's Message to Congree; Farm Legislation
  - Agricultural Act, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Congressional record; bills; statements; press releases regarding Act; Gordon Roth; memos regarding surplus, wheat, and House Representative Edward J. Thye, Minnesota
  - Agricultural Act, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Bills, statements, press releases regarding Act
  - Agricultural Act, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Correspondence, press releases, statements regarding Act; M.W. Thatcher, President, NFGC to Roy F. Hendrickson St. Paul
  - Agricultural Act, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Press releases, reports, clippings, correspondence regarding 1954; includes "Appraisal of the Agricultural Acts of 1948 and 1949 … by Ezra T. Benson … (by) Iowa State College …" Mimeograph( June 4, 1953) 8 pp.; correspondents: Edward J. Thye, Senate, Minnesota, Harold D. Cooley, House, N. Caroline, R.F.H to Clifford R. Hope, House, Kansas
  - Agricultural Act, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Congressional record, clippings, correspondence regarding Act; USDA Milton R. Young, Senate, N. Dakota (copy of letter Apr. 14, 1953) regarding parity prices
  - Agricultural Act, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Bills regarding Act
  - Agricultural Act, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Mostly correspondence including Harold D. Cooley, House, N. Carolina regarding parity; Milton R. Young, Senate, N. Dakota regarding "Young-Russell" bill
  - Agricultural Act (Anderson Bill), 1949 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Text of the Act
  - Agricultural Act (Aiken Bill), 1948 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Text of the Act; also Roy F. Hendrickson to M.W. Thatcher on the Act (Nov. 6, 1948); 2 pp. plus 10 pp. comments on agricultural situation
- Series II. Co-op Taxes
  - Co-op Taxes, Briefing Conference 1962, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Includes registration list of attendees and 3 copies "Legislative Background of the New Tax Treatment of Cooperatives and their Patrons" by John E. Noakes, New York (Nov. 19-20, 1962), Washington D.C. 9 pp. + 2 pp. footnotes
  - Co-op Taxes, H R 13103 -- Foreign Investors Tax Act of 1966, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Includes bill and Roy F. Hendrickson letters to Eugene McCarthy, Senate, Minnesota, and Frank Carlson, Senate, Kansas regarding section 212 which relates to cooperatives
  - Co-op Taxes, Cooperative Marketing Association, Kansas City, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Mostly correspondence regarding IRS and CMA and income tax exemption status
  - Cooperatives, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Copy of Cache Valley Case, 1965; copy of "Farmers' Cooperative Income Tax Returns for 1953" IRS
  - Co-op Taxes, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Correspondence regarding cooperatives and taxation with Kansas Farmers' Service Association and memo from Nieman and Bosard, Attorneys, Minneapolis regarding "the question of income tax on government business"
  - Co-op Taxes, Kansas Brief, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Protest and covering letter regarding taxing of copperatives with protest from The Cooperative Elevator and Supply Company, Meade, Kansas, 23 pp., Confidential
  - Co-op Taxes, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Mostly correspondence regarding Interal Revenue and cooperatives, and matter of capital retains
  - Co-op Taxes - Capital Retains, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Includes memos from Roy F. Hendrickson to Directors; and copies of Federal Register
  - Co-op Taxes Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Telegrams, resolutions, regarding cooperative taxes; National Council of Farmer Cooperatives, Homer L. Brinkely, W.E. Rumble (St. Paul, Attorneys), Cooperative League of the United States, Jerry Voorhis (Ex Director)
  - Co-op Taxes, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    NFGC Directors regarding amendment to HR 10650, Texas, Kansas, Iowa; Correspondence with Nebraksa, New York, etc.
  - Co-op Taxes, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Statement, W.E. Rumble (Apr 16, 1962) before Senate, Committee on Finance, 10 pp. mimeograph
  - Co-op Taxes, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Mostly correspondence to and from Dr. A Ladru Jensen, Attorney, Salt Lake City regarding taxation of cooperatives including "Summary of Revenue Act of Oct 1962 As it Applies to Cooperatives" 5 pp.; also 6 pp. mimeograph statement/letter from Ladru to Senator Wallace F. Bennett (May 7, 1962) regarding HR 10650; National Rural Electric Cooperative Association; National Council of Farmer Cooperatives
  - Co-op Taxes, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Mr. Max M. Kampelman, Attorney, Washington, memo to Senator Eugene McCarthy (June 16, 1962), 6 pp., plus 2 pp. supplemental (copy) memo is regarding HR 10650 and taxation of cooperatives
  - Co-op Taxes, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Includes copy of letter sent to Senators Robert S. Kerr, Eugene McCarthy, Frank Carlson, Carl T. Curtis regarding Senator Clinton Anderson proposal of taxing cooperatives
  - Co-op Taxes, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    National Council of Farmer Cooperatives and HR 10650 correspondence and memos
  - Co-op Taxes, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Some literature of the National Tax Equality Association (1962) and article of taxing cooperatives which appeared in the READERS DIGEST (Feb 1962)
  - Co-op Taxes - 1961 Legislation, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Mostly statement, Douglas Dillon, Ways and Means Committee (May 3, 1961), subject is taxation; also Roy F. Hendrickson newsletter on taxes (Apr 21, 1961); and press release, White House, "Message on Taxation" (Apr 20, 1961)
  - Co-op Taxes - House, Ways and Means Committee, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Includes Roy F. Hendrickson to Wilbur D. Mills, House, and also RGH newsletter (Jan 20, 1959); and Frank G Rankin, Manager, Golf Proof Elevator, Louisville, Kentucky to Roy F. Hendrickson (Nov 20, 1958) regarding Representative John C. Watts, Kentucky, and Mr. Clarence L. Miller, Assistant Secretary of Agriculture, regarding their stand on cooperatives (Watts and Miller) "good for agriculture"
  - Co-op Taxes, 1958-01-27 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Statement, W.E. Rumble before Ways and Means Committee, mimeograph, 25 pp.
  - Co-op Taxes, 1951-03-01 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Statement, W.E. Rumble, Ways and Means Committee, 6 pp., mimeograph
  - W.E. Rumble, 1951-07 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Statement, W.E. Rumble, Taxation and cooperatives, 29 pp. mimeo.
  - Daniel A. Reed, 1951-07-20 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Statement, Congressional Record regarding taxation
  - Daniel A. Reed, 1951-03-20 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Co-op Taxes - IRS Hearing, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Statement of Karl D. Loos (Feb 23, 1950) before Ways and Means Committee, 35 pp., 3 tables, mimeo
  - Co-op Taxes - IRS Hearing, 1963-02-19 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Correspondence, other items regarding hearing
  - Co-op Taxes - Revenue Ruling, 1963-01-08 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Roy F. Hendrickson, newsletter, 30 pp., mimeograph regarding IRS proposed regulations regarding cooperative taxes
  - Co-op Taxes - Omaha District (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Correspondence (2 letters) between Roy F. Hendrickson and Robert C. Guenzel, Attorney, Lincoln regarding cooperatives and IRS
  - Co-op Taxes - Legislation, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    Bill, HR 4370 (Feb 4, 1965)
  - Co-op Taxes - Tax Court Decisions, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Some correspondence and briefs regarding Northwest Agricultural Cooperative Association v. ICC, Ninth Circuit Court of Appeals (Aug 10, 1965)
  - Co-op Taxes - General, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    Mostly correspondence regarding letter Mr. Lester R. McDonald, Farmers Elevator and Merchandise Company, Satanta, Kansas to Representative Floyd Breeding, 5th District, Kansas (May 16, 1958) regarding taxation of cooperatives that they should be taxed; Roy F. Hendrickson assisted in reply from Breeding to McDonald
  - Co-op Taxes - General, 1951, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    Correspondence, clippings, pamphlets; includes letter, James G. Patton to Roy F. Hendrickson (Mar 19 1956) saying they should visit tax problems and "concerned that we may have some substantially punitive legislation if this crows stays in office"; Confidential Report on Conference on United Action for Tax Justice, Chicago (Oct 12, 1956), 6 pp. mimeo; Roy F. Hendrickson (May 24, 1956) Draft of Proposed Tax Amendment (Confidential) to Directors; Senator Hubert H. Humphrey to Roy F. Hendrickson; (Dec. 30, 1955) regarding taxation of cooperatives
  - Income Tax - Co-op Taxes - Legislation, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    Correspondence, reports, bills regarding tax legislation; includes Homer L. Brinkley to Roy F.H. and others (Mar 16, 1956) on meeting with members; Ways and Means (Cooper, Mills, Boggs, and Daniel A. Reed) states their feelings on current legislation before them; 2pp confidential
  - Co-op Taxes, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    Correspondence and draft of proposed tax legislation from National Council of Farmer Cooperatives
  - Co-op Taxes, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    Correspondence, newsletters, clippings regarding taxation of cooperatives
  - Co-op Taxes - Commodity Credit Corporation grain, 1956-1962 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Correspondence, memos, reports regarding Commodity Credit Corporation; Roy F. Hendrickson, Fred Maywald, Farmers Grain Dealers Association, Des Moines
  - Co-op Taxes, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Ways and Means Committee hearings; W.E. Rumble and Roy F. Hendrickson some good letters regarding hearings (Jan 1958); some copies of statements, some publications
  - Co-op Taxes, 1958-1963 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Correspondence; copies from Congressional Record
  - Co-op Taxes, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Correspondence regarding Westcentral and Maywood (Nebraska) cooperative tax cases
- Series III. Import Quotas
  - Alcone, S.M. - Comtelburo-Reuters, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Commodity prices
  - McVey, Dan, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Dan H. McVey, Chief, Grain Branch, USDA, 6 mimeograph reports on grain cooperatives throughout the U.S.
  - McVey, Dan, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    4 mimeo, reports on grain cooperatives, United States
  - Import Quotas, 1952-1955 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Correspondence, memos, editorials; series of memos and letters to M.W. Thatcher, General Manager, Farmers Union Grain Terminal Association, St. Paul regarding Canada and grain imports
  - Import Quotas - Barley, 1953-1956 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Correspondence, newsletters, reports regarding imports of barley; Roy F. Hendrickson to Senators Milton R. Young, Karl E. Mundt, Edward J. Thye (Jan 17, 1954) a super memo on the situation; also reply from Mundt and subsequent eltter of Roy F. Hendrickson to Mundt (Jan 26, 1954) regarding barley import situation
  - Import Quotas - Congressional Hearings, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Correspondence includes Milton R. Young, George D. Aiken, Francis Case and statement of M.W. Thatcher, St. Paul (Apr 23, 1953) before Senate Committee on Agriculture and Forestry; also testimony, C.L. Dickinson, Grange League Federation (Apr 23, 1953)
  - Import Quotas - Customs Bureau, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Includes Roy F. Hendrickson to Non. Franklin Dow, Customs (Dec 3 1952) 6pp. Letter on definition of wheat, unfit for human consumption
  - Import Quotas - Regulations, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Includes 2 copies of USDA Regulations
  - Agricultural Adjustment Act - Section 22, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    6 pp. letter-statement of M.W. Thatcher (May 17, 1954) regarding imports of grain and the Agricultural Adjustment Act sent to numerous Senators and Congressmen and some replies to Thatcher statement - including Senators Hubert H. Humphrey, Milton R. Young, William Langer; also, report of US Government regarding Act (Oct 1955) 23 pp. mimeo
  - Import Quotas - USDA Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Includes letters from Secretary of Agriculture, Charles F. Brannen (Sep 10, 1952); also letter True D. Morse, and from some members of Congress, as Milton R. Young and Edward J. Thye
  - Import Quotas - Wallace letter regarding Feed grains, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Includes copy of letter Henry A. Wallace, to Secretary of Treasurery (Feb 1, 1953) 3 pp. regarding "unfit for human consumption" and Roy F. Hendrickson sending it to Congressmen in 1954
  - Import Quotas - Durum wheat, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Roy F. Hendrickson (Dec 21, 1954) to Walter C. Berger, Commodity Stabilization Service, 3pp on durum wheat and some comments from Congressmen regarding that letter and situation in Congress
  - Wheat Unfit for Human Consumption - S 1313 Bill, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Correspondence regarding Roy F. Hendrickson and Congressman regarding NFGC and their support for the bill, includes H. Carl Anderson, House, Minnesota and Milton R. Young and Don L. Short
  - Imports - Feed Wheat, 1953-1955 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Correspondence includes Roy F. Hendrickson to Karl D. Loos, Solicitor, USDA (Jan 26, 1954) on unfit wheat, letters and reports; E.J. Bell, Grain and Feed Division, USDA (Feb 11, 1965) to Roy F. Hendrickson on Canadian wheat; clippings; statement, Roy F. Hendrickson (Jun 10, 1953), Senate Judiciary Committee on S. 784 unfit wheat; 12 pp. mimeo
  - Import Quotas - Oats, 1951-1953 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Includes correspondence, reports and clippings regarding oats and imports; Roy F. Hendrickson to Milton R. Young (Sep 1, 1953) and Young to Roy F. Hendrickson (Aug 25, 1953) on quotas and also general farm situation; several statements, including Prof L.C. Cunningham, Cornell (Jul 9, 1953) regarding importation of oats; 3 pp. plus tables; "Investigation of Importation of Oats from Canada," USDA, about 30 pp., mimeograph (Oct 15, 1952)
  - Import Quotas - Rye, 1955-1961 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Statement and correspondence on rye and imports; Roy F. Hendrickson statement (Jun 15, 1955), 6 pp, US Tariff Commission; correspondence on rye situation and includes Hubert H. Humphrey, Milton R. Young, Lawrence F. O'Brien, Dean Acheson, Karl E. Mundt, Edward J. Thye
  - Imports of Canadian Grain - Defense Production Act, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 21)